# **CARTER BROWN**

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email: me@carterbrown.dev Location: Tucson, Arizona

Github: http://github.com/developercarter/

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/carterbrown2/

Portfolio: https://www.carterbrown.dev/

# **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 2 years of experience crafting concise and quality code. Also offering another two years of customer service experience, practicing satisfying end-users and collaborating effectively within a team. Experienced with all aspects of the software development life-cycle and full stack application development.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-end: Javascript, HTML, CSS, React.js/React Hooks, JQuery, AJAX Bootstrap, Material UI

**Back-end:** Python, Flask, Node.js, Java, Jinja2, WTForms, Express, JQuery

Testing: Jasmine, Jest, Supertest, Unit Testing, Integration Testing

**Databases:** PostgresQL, SQLAlchemy, SQL, pg, AWS **Other:** Heroku, Github, Bootstrap, Material UI, JSX, REST

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Springboard** – Software Engineering Fellow

### Weatherly

- Fully functional weather website.
- Built with Flask/Python and Jinja2 templating engine.
- Includes Authentication through sign in/sign up.
- Linked to a PostgresQL relational database, which stores users and locations. Storing locations prevents multiple requests for the same location.

Deployed at: <a href="https://carter-weatherly.herokuapp.com">https://carter-weatherly.herokuapp.com</a>

### NNC

- News website built with newsapi.org's public API
- Built with React.js front-end and Node.js back-end
- Includes Authentication and Authorization, only users are allowed to view articles.
- Information for each article and user information stored in PostgresQL database.

### Warbler

- Twitter-esque web application.
- Built with Python/Flask and Jinja2 templating engine to serve HTML pages.
- Includes Authentication and Authorization for each user, only allowing those with an account to tweet.
- Allows you to create and view other profiles, while also allowing you to update and delete your own.

Deployed at: <a href="https://carter-warbler.herokuapp.com">https://carter-warbler.herokuapp.com</a>

## **Professional Detailer, Detail and Dash**

Superior, WI - March 2020 to March 2021

- Professional car detailing/customer service role.
- Working together with a group of 6, detailing each car in teams of two.
- Achieved ~50% increase in revenue compared to previous year while I was there due to our efficiency as a team.

## Spa Attendant, Canyon Ranch

Tucson, AZ – November 2021 - May 2022

- Client-facing customer service role.
- Collaborated with a team of around 20.
- Tend to the needs/wants of hundreds of high-profile guests.
- Decreased customer complaints by 66%.
- Slashed spending on cleaning products for the Spa by ~30%.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Springboard, Certification – January 2021 to October 2021

An 800+ hour course covers key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Modules include learning resources, practice exercises, projects, and career-related coursework.

## freeCodeCamp, Certification – July 2020 to December 2020

Responsive web design certification, included 300+ hours of more coursework and projects, covering how to make responsive websites that won't break on smaller screens and introducing.

## **Superior High School, Diploma**

Superior, Wisconsin - Game Development I & II